<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alex Novacovschi</title>
    <link>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alex Novacovschi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 11:07:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Telegram bot on python</title>
      <link>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/python-telegram-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 11:07:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/python-telegram-bot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Once upon a time I had a need to for a telegram bot that will reposts news from external channels to my own channel to stay up-to-day with news from different sources in one place. Doing some short research, I didn’t found suitable open-source script for my needs and I decided to write my own script on python. It is not ideal, but it works :-)
There is a library called Telethon  that makes easy to write python applications that can interact with Telegram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Disk Encryption for Linux VMs</title>
      <link>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/ade-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:02:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/ade-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>Azure provides disk encryption option for Iaas virtual machines, this is a perfect solution for those who want to keep data encrypted with own keys. Some aspects I would like to clarify here to have a more transparent solution. I have tested and implemented this solution. Ok, lets have some fun&amp;hellip;
There are some prerequests before we can start to encrypt our disks.  Azure Disk Encryption is only supported on specific Azure Gallery based Linux server distributions and versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme Demo</title>
      <link>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/theme-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/theme-demo/</guid>
      <description>Style Demo h1 Heading h2 Heading h3 Heading h4 Heading h5 Heading h6 Heading This is bold text
This is bold text
This is italic text
This is italic text
Deleted text
This is text with inline math $\sum_{n=1}^{\infty} 2^{-n} = 1$ and with math blocks:
$$ \sum_{n=1}^{\infty} 2^{-n} = 1 $$
   Heading Another heading     text text   text text   text text     Block quotes are written like so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novy4.github.io/novy.pw/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>